037 利用VisualStateManager来创建自适应的触发器 （翻译 by Elenore）
大家好，我是Bob Tabor
Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with
来自www.LearnVisualStudio.net
www.LearnVisualStudio.net, and I want you to take a look
我们先看一下屏幕
on-screen right now because
因为我要展示一个效果
I wanted to illustrate an idea,
这样你们更好理解
it's easier to show you than explain it.
这是一个简单的app，只用了一个grid
Here I have a simple application with a Grid,
把它的背景颜色设为红色
I set the Grid's Background="Red"
我还写了一个简单的文本块
and I have a simple TextBlock and I've got a,
字体大小大概是16pt或者18pt
I don't know, 16 point, 18 point font there.
注意看，当我改变它的大小时发生了什么
And so watch what happens though whenever I resize this.
当我把它改变到一定大小时
I get to a certain point and
就触发了一些变化
it triggers the change of the BackgroundColor
它的背景颜色变成了黄色，字体也变大了
to Yellow, and the FontSize to a larger FontSize,
大概是24pt的样子
I think like 24 or something.
好我们继续改变（它的大小）
Now let's continue to resize,
背景颜色变成了蓝色
and the Cackground color changes to blue
文本块的字体变的更大了
and I use an even larger Font for the TextBlock.
这些之所以能发生呢
And so this is made possible by an object called
都是因为我们用了一个叫 VisualStateManager 的对象
the VisualStateManager and it does
就像它的名字那样说的
exactly what it sounds like, it manages
它用来管理app的视觉状态
the visual state of your application,
比如大小
where things belong, the sizes of things,
颜色，这些都是通过你创建的触发器来实现的
the colors of things based on Triggers that you create.
所以，基本上你可以处理任何对象的任何属性
So, essentially you can manipulate any property
你可以在改变大小时
of any object, you can resize,
改变位置时，来设置可见性
reposition, set the visibility,
设置字体大小，设置字体样式
you can set the FontSize, set the FontFamily.
任何你能想到的
Anything that you possibly can imagine
（这些变化）都是基于当时的窗口大小
based on the current size of the window,
或者当时的屏幕面积
or the current available screen real estate.
可以想一想这么把这些
And so think about how that applies to the
应用到UWP上
Universal Windows Platform.
这其中一个亮点在于
One of the selling points is that you're able
你可以只写一份基础的代码
to write one code base and then use it
然后它就可以用在各种不同外形的场景下
across all these different form factors.
这让你（的app）可以适应
And so this allows you to accommodate different
不同屏幕分辨率的设备
screen resolutions for different form factors
然而代码都是一样的
with the same code base.
这个基本概念
And so this is a very foundational concept
就是我们这节课要讲的
and what we're going to talk about briefly in this lesson,
我们还会讲到这个如何应用于自适应的布局
we'll talk about how this applies to adaptive layout,
换句话说，就是改变app的整个布局
in other words, changing the entire layout
基于屏幕的大小
of your application based on the screen size,
即外形因素
the form factor.
这个我们下个视频会讲到
We'll talk about that in the very next video.
再强调一遍，这个概念可以实现都是因为
But again, this is all made possible because of
一个叫 VisualStateManager 的对象
a object called the VisualStateManager,
你要创建一个VisualStateGroup，然后在这个里面
You create a VisualStateGroup and inside of that group
你可以创建一组状态
you create a series of States.
状态可以是任何，你要给它命名
So a State can be anything, you give it a name
还要写一些触发器
and you give it some Triggers.
那我们来看一下
So in this case take a look at
刚刚那个app的代码
the application we were just looking at.
这里我写了一个叫VisualStatePhone的状态
So here I have a VisualState that I called Phone.
和一个叫VisualStateTablet的状态
I have another VisualState that I called Tablet,
or VisualStateTablet,
还有一个状态
And then another VisualState
叫VisualStateDesktop
that I called VisualStateDesktop.
你可以按自己喜好命名
Now you can name these things anything you want to.
我不知道有没有标准大小
And I don't know if there's any standard sizes or
或者其它让你觉得为难的地方
anything that you've got to stick with.
它都是有意义的
It's whatever makes sense for your application,
这就是我觉得测试app
and that's why I think, you know, testing your application
需要不停地在不同的设备上（测试）
continually on different devices, and VisualStudio
而Visual Studio让这件事变得简单
obviously makes that very simple.
在尽可能多的不同外形的场景下测试
But testing it as many different form factors as possible,
会帮助你得到最佳的布局效果
will help you see the optimal layout
在不同的外形场景下
for that given form factor.
好哒我们来看看代码
So here we go, we have a VisualState.
一个 VisualState 包含两个东西
And a VisualState is comprised of two things.
一个是一组触发器
First of all, a series of Triggers
还有一组Setters
and then a series of Setters.
在这种情况下，触发器本质上是
So when a Trigger is essentially, in this case,
不管是最小窗口宽度（MinWindowWidth）
either the MinWindowWidth,
还是最小窗口高度（MinWindowHeight）
or the MinWindowHeight,
一旦满足条件，就会触发
that once it's achieved will Trigger
表现为特定的视觉状态（VisualState）
this particular VisualState.
所以，一旦一个状态被触发了
So once that State is Triggered,
Setters就起作用了
then it applies these Setters.
这些Setters很像
And these Setters are very similar to the Setters
我们在样式中使用的Setters，对吧
that we had in Styles right?
有一个“Target”属性
Where we have a Target, property,
这是一个叫“ColorGrid”的对象
so here's the object, the ColorGrid object.
我要把它的背景颜色设为红色
And I'm going to set the Background Value="Red".
对文本块也是一样的处理
Alright, same thing with the TextBlock,
用MessageTextBlock
this MessageTextBlock.
我用了点（.）操作符，这样我们可以访问
And I use the dot notation just like we would to access
对象的成员了，这是C#的语法
members of an object in C#.
所以我们用点操作符来访问FontSize属性
So we use the dot notation to access the property FontSize
我们把它的值设为18，当我们处于
and we set it's value to 18, whenever we are in that
窗口宽度大于0的时候，因为最小窗口宽度为0
smallest state where the MinWindowWidth="0".
下一个状态的触发器
The next State up has a Trigger
设置的最小窗口宽度是600
of MinWindowWidth="600".
当满足最小窗口宽度时
And at that point then we were applying,
我们写的Setters就会
the Setters that we're applying are setting the
把 ColorGrid 的背景颜色设为黄色
background ColorGrid to yellow,
同时文本块的字体设为36pt
and the FontSize of the MessageTextBlock to 36.
对于桌面级的外形
And then finally the desktop, as long as the
最小窗口宽度设为800
MinWindowWidth="800",
一旦窗口宽度达到最小值
once we stretch it out that far,
app的背景颜色就会
then we were able to change the Background
变成蓝色，字体大小变为54
to blue and the FontSize to 54.
所以从概念上讲，这个还蛮简单的
So conceptually it's easy,
非常简单
it's very easy.
它让你可以做很多创造性的事情
It allows you to get creative
当你想让你的app发生一些改变时
with how you want to make changes to your application
就用这个（VisualStateManager）吧
using this tool.
这就是我们要讲的概念
And that's really all there is to the notion of
在这个视频中
what we were calling in the video
叫做自适应触发器（AdaptiveTrigger）
an AdaptiveTrigger.
这是一个AdaptiveTrigger对象
Here's an AdaptiveTrigger object,
我们写了一个触发器，然后
we set the Trigger and then once that Trigger is
一旦这个触发器被触发，Setters就起作用了
fired off, we apply the Setters.
好棒
Ok great.
现在我要给你看的是
Now I wanted to show you
有一个工具可以帮助你来做这些
that there's actually a tool that will help you do this.
事实上我并不喜欢这个工具
Now I don't like this tool, honestly,
我真的是很诚实地告诉你哦
I'm being completely honest with you,
我其实更喜欢自己手写
I would prefer to do it by hand,
这样感觉有更多主导权
I feel like I have more control.
但是如果你更喜欢视觉化的操作
But if you're a more visual type person
然后你也不记得那么多语法
and you don't remember the syntax
你还不想查参考手册
and you don't want to look up on your cheat sheet,
我们等会儿会把这个加到参考手册里去
as we'll add this to our cheat sheet in a little bit,
你就可以用这个懒方法啦
you can use this trick.
在解决方案资源管理器里，看到你的项目
In your project, in the Solution Explorer,
你可以看到
you can see here I have
我有一个新项目，名字叫UsingBlendForVisualStates
a New Project called UsingBlendForVisualStates,
我还写了同样的“ColorGrid”和文本块
and I have the same Color Grid and TextBlock,
不过还没有添加任何东西在里面
but I haven't added anything else to it just yet.
在解决方案资源管理器里面，右击项目名
Here in the Solution Explorer I'm going to right-click
选择在Blend中设计
on the project and select Design in Blend.
Blend是一个工具
And so Blend is a tool that should be installed
随Visual Studio一起下载的
along with Visual Studio
它主要是做一些设计类的工作
And it really was intended for
我的意思是通过设计来实现
more design work, and by design I mean
美术设计之类的工作
aesthetic design work.
你可以看到它和Visual Studio
And you see that it has many of the same
有很多相同的功能
features of Visual Studio.
右边是属性窗口
On the right-hand side we have the properties window.
解决方案资源管理器默认停靠在这里
There is also a Solution Explorer docked by default
这左边
over here on the left.
Blend帮你做了两件事
There are two things that Blend does for you
这两件事呢，你自己做起来可能不那么容易
that you can't easily do
在Visual Studio
in Visual Studio.
其中一件事呢
And one of them, is it gives you this cool little
就是让你很cool地创建VisualState
way of creating VisualStates and
并且记录状态的改变
recording the changes in a given State.
另一件事呢，就是动画结合起来
And then secondly, working with animation,
这个我们不打算在这系列讲到
which we're not going to talk about in this series.
让我来展示给你看Blend是怎么工作的吧
But let me show you how this works,
事实上它超简单
in fact it's just easier if I go straight
要是我直接到设计界面的话to the design view for this.
让我们来看看
And let's go down to where we can actually see
我们的设计区
our design area.
这是对象和时间轴窗口
So there's this Objects and Timeline window,
一般停靠在左边
typically docked on the left-hand side.
你看我可以向下展开
And you can see that I can drill down and see
看到ColorGrid和它里面包含的东西
the ColorGrid and whatever's inside the ColorGrid,
一个MessageTextBlock
in this case, the MessageTextBlock.
然后我要看看状态标签
And then I'm going to go to the States tab here
一般停靠在左上角
that's usually docked up on the upper left-hand corner.
我要添加一个状态组
And what I'll do is, I'm going to add a state group,
所以我点一下这个小按钮
so I'm going to click this little button here.
然后它就会创建一个VisualStateGroup
And this will create a VisualStateGroup.
我要添加一个状态到这个状态组里
I'm going to add a state to that group
将它命名为Phone
d I'm going to call this state Phone,
我们可以按自己想法命名
we can call it anything we want.
我还要添加一个状态
I'm going to add another state
这个叫Tablet
that I'm going to call Tablet.
我还要添加一个叫Desktop的状态
And I'm going to add another state that I call Desktop.
注意到当我选择它们其中任意一个时
And notice that whenever I select any of these,
这里会出现一个小红点
that a little red light
在被选择的状态的左边
is selected on the left-hand side,
同时在设计区会出现红色的边框
and there's a red border all around the designer area.
你可能看到状态Phone就开始记录了
You might also see that Phone state recording is on.
现在我选择了状态Tablet，然后状态Tablet就开始记录了
Now I select Tablet and Tablet state recording is on
所以基本上你要做的就是
So essentially what you're doing here is,
记录属性窗口中
you're recording the changes in the property window
你想要的变化
that you want to be made
在你选择的状态下
when you're in that given state.
现在我们还有一些其他事需要做
Now there's something else that we need to do
在我们继续下去之前
before we actually continue on with this.
那就是，我们要设置触发器
And that is, we need to set the Triggers.
就像你在这里看到的
So as you can see here,
这有一个闪电样的标志
there's a little lightning bolt
在右边
off to the right-hand side
我要点击它（编辑自适应触发器）I'm going to click Edit Adaptive Triggers,
我要添加一个AdaptiveTrigger
and I'm going to add an AdaptiveTrigger,
把它的MinWindowWidth设置成0
and set in this case the MinWindowWidth to zero,
点击OK
and click OK.
接下来是状态Tablet
And then for Tablet,
我要把MinWindowWidth设成600
I'm going to set it's MinWindowWidth I think to 600,
这其实是我随便输的数字啦
again these are arbitrary numbers,
你可以为自己的app测试一下
you would want to test this for your own application,
我感觉这个没有绝对的标准
there are no standards that I'm aware of,
你应该要使用断点
at certain break points you should be using
与之相对的是，我觉得这些应该
this versus that, I think this is something you get
由你这个开发者来决定
to determine on your own as the developer.
所以，当窗口宽度大于等于600，就会触发
So the MinWindowWidth 600, that will trigger
状态Tablet，最后我们来设置状态Desktopt
he Tablet state, and then finally the Desktop,
我们把它的最小值设为800
we'll set it's minimum to 800.
在这里
So here.
800，好了
800 great.
当处于状态Desktop时
Now, whenever in Desktop mode,
我们想做什么呢，我要选择MessageTextBlock
what we want to do, I'm going to select the MessageTextBlock
在这个对象和时间轴窗口里
here in the Objects and Timeline window.
我要改变它的字体
And then I'm going to change the font
大小改成54，我不记得我们刚开始那个数值了
to oh let's say 54, I forget what we chose originally.
接下来我要设置状态Tablet
And then I'm going to go to the Tablet,
我要修改这个文本块
and then I'm going to change the TextBlock
大小是36
to let's say 36.
然后是状态Phone
And then I'm going to go to the Phone
把它的字体大小改到16
and change it to like 16.
继续
And so now, let me go ahead
保存
save what I have,
运行
and then I'm going to run the application.
你看
And you can see
这些变化就实现了
that I was able to make those changes
都是用这个工具实现的
using this tool.
再强调一遍，我个人是比较喜欢自己敲代码来实现的
Now again, I would prefer to just type it in myself.
它确实创建了一个漂亮干净的XAML，但是有些地方
It does create nice clean XAML, but there are some cases
比如处理颜色，处理笔刷
like working with colors, and brushes,
我就不喜欢它生成的XAML
I didn't like the XAML that it outputted.
我更愿意自己手打
That's me just being a little snobby here.
当然你可以用这个工具来帮助自己
But otherwise you can use this tool to help you
生成一些东西
generate these sorts of things.
当你关闭Blend的时候
Now when you close down Blend,
你就会返回到Visual Studio
you're going to come back into VisualStudio,
它就会提示你，你是不是刚刚打开了一些窗口
it says hey, any windows that you had open,
它们在Visual Studio之外的地方被改变了
they changed out from under VisualStudio.
你想要重新加载吗
Do you want to reload this?
当然，我要重新加载，然后你就看到
Yes, I want to reload it and now you can see
所有的Visual States
All of the visual States
还有触发器和Setters
and the Triggers and the Setters
它们在Visual Studio都被更新了
are all updated here in VisualStudio.
所以呢，这一个很简单的概念，很有用
So again, a very simple concept, very powerful
在我们如何用这个
in how we can go about using this
去样式化我们的app
to style up our applications based on the
根据不同的外形因素和分辨率方面
form factor and screen resolution.
再多说一遍，这是基本的概念
And again, foundational concept for building real
在我们创建一个真正的UWP的app中
Universal Windows Platform applications.
我们要用到这个
And so we're going to use this now
在接下来的课程中
in the next lesson to actually
来创建更多实用的app
create a more realistic app,
利用这些概念来改变布局
and utilize these concepts to change out the layout
基于可用的屏幕分辨率
based on the available screen resolution.
好哒，我们就要进入激动人心的第二部分了
Alright so stay tuned to exciting part two of this
下节课见 (￣▽￣)"
in the very next lesson, thanks.